<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>atomic on The Odd Bit</title>

  
  <link rel="self" href="http://blog.oddbit.com/tags/atomic/atom.xml"/>
  
  <link href="http://blog.oddbit.com/tags/atomic/" rel="alternate"></link>                                      │1557152283 127.0.0.1 "GET /dist/styles.css" 304 136 "http://localhost:1313/" "Mozilla/5.0 (X11;

  <updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://blog.oddbit.com/tags/atomic/</id>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Running NTP in a Container</title>
    <author>Lars Kellogg-Stedman</author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-10-09-running-ntp-in-a-container/"/>
    <id>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-10-09-running-ntp-in-a-container/</id>
    <published>2015-10-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary>Someone asked on IRC about running ntpd in a container on Atomic, so I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a small example. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a very simple Dockerfile:
FROM alpine RUN apk update RUN apk add openntpd ENTRYPOINT [&amp;quot;ntpd&amp;quot;]  I&amp;rsquo;m using the alpine image as my starting point because it&amp;rsquo;s very small, which makes this whole process go a little faster. I&amp;rsquo;m installing the openntpd package, which provides the ntpd binary.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Heat-kubernetes Demo with Autoscaling</title>
    <author>Lars Kellogg-Stedman</author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-06-19-heatkubernetes-demo-with-autoscaling/"/>
    <id>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-06-19-heatkubernetes-demo-with-autoscaling/</id>
    <published>2015-06-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-06-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary>Next week is the Red Hat Summit in Boston, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking part in a Project Atomic presentation in which I will discuss various (well, two) options for deploying Atomic into an OpenStack environment, focusing on my heat-kubernetes templates.
As part of that presentation, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a short demonstration video:
 This shows off the autoscaling behavior available with recent versions of these templates (and also serves as a very brief introduction to working with Kubernetes).</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Fedora Atomic, OpenStack, and Kubernetes (oh my)</title>
    <author>Lars Kellogg-Stedman</author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2014-11-24-fedora-atomic-openstack-and-kubernetes-oh-my/"/>
    <id>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2014-11-24-fedora-atomic-openstack-and-kubernetes-oh-my/</id>
    <published>2014-11-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary>While experimenting with Fedora Atomic, I was looking for an elegant way to automatically deploy Atomic into an OpenStack environment and then automatically schedule some Docker containers on the Atomic host. This post describes my solution.
Like many other cloud-targeted distributions, Fedora Atomic runs cloud-init when the system boots. We can take advantage of this to configure the system at first boot by providing a user-data blob to Nova when we boot the instance.</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
