<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pull-request on The Odd Bit</title>
    <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/pull-request/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pull-request on The Odd Bit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/pull-request/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding support for privilege escalation to Ansible&#39;s docker connection driver</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2019-04-26-adding-support-for-privilege-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2019-04-26-adding-support-for-privilege-e/</guid>
      <description>Update 2019-05-09 Pull request #55816 has merged, so you can now use sudo with the docker connection driver even when sudo is configured to require a password.
 I often use Docker to test out Ansible playbooks. While normally that works great, I recently ran into an unexpected problem with privilege escalation. Given a simple playbook like this:
--- - hosts: all gather_facts: false become: true tasks: - ping:  And an inventory like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Bitwarden with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2018-10-19-integrating-bitwarden-with-ans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2018-10-19-integrating-bitwarden-with-ans/</guid>
      <description>Bitwarden is a password management service (like LastPass or 1Password). It&amp;rsquo;s unique in that it is built entirely on open source software. In addition to the the web UI and mobile apps that you would expect, Bitwarden also provides a command-line tool for interacting with the your password store.
At $WORK(-ish) we&amp;rsquo;re looking into Bitwarden because we want a password sharing and management solution that was better than dropping files into directories on remote hosts or sharing things over Slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A systemd-nspawn connection driver for Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-08-a-systemd-nspawn-connection-driver-for-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-08-a-systemd-nspawn-connection-driver-for-a/</guid>
      <description>I wrote earlier about systemd-nspawn, and how it can take much of the fiddly work out of setting up functional chroot environments. I&amp;rsquo;m a regular Ansible user, and I wanted to be able to apply some of those techniques to my playbooks.
Ansible already has a chroot module, of course, but for some situations &amp;ndash; such as targeting an emulated chroot environment &amp;ndash; that just means a lot of extra work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folding long lines in Ansible inventory files</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-07-folding-long-lines-in-ansible-inventory-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-07-folding-long-lines-in-ansible-inventory-/</guid>
      <description>If you have an Ansible inventory file that includes lots of per host variables, it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for lines to get long enough that they become unwieldly, particularly if you want to discuss them in an email or write about them in some context (e.g., a blog post).
I&amp;rsquo;ve just submitted pull request #14359 to Ansible which implements support for folding long lines using the INI-format convention of using indent to mark extended logical lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible 2.0: New OpenStack modules</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-10-26-ansible-20-new-openstack-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-10-26-ansible-20-new-openstack-modules/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a loose sequence of articles looking at new features in Ansible 2.0. In the previous article I looked at the Docker connection driver. In this article, I would like to provide an overview of the new-and-much-improved suite of modules for interacting with an OpenStack environment, and provide a few examples of their use.
In versions of Ansible prior to 2.0, there was a small collection of OpenStack modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teach git about GIT_SSL_CIPHER_LIST</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-05-08-git-ssl-cipher-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2015-05-08-git-ssl-cipher-list/</guid>
      <description>Someone named hithard on StackOverflow was trying to clone a git repository via https, and was running into an odd error: &amp;ldquo;Cannot communicate securely with peer: no common encryption algorithm(s).&amp;rdquo;. This was due to the fact that the server (openhatch.org) was configured to use a cipher suite that was not supported by default in the underlying SSL library (which could be either OpenSSL or NSS, depending on how git was built).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker plugin bugs</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2014-09-01-docker-plugin-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2014-09-01-docker-plugin-bugs/</guid>
      <description>This is a companion to my article on the Docker plugin for Heat.
While writing that article, I encountered a number of bugs in the Docker plugin and elsewhere. I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted patches for most of the issues I encountered:
Bugs in the Heat plugin   https://bugs.launchpad.net/heat/+bug/1364017
docker plugin fails to delete a container resource in CREATE_FAILED state.
  https://bugs.launchpad.net/heat/+bug/1364041
docker plugin volumes_from parameter should be a list.
  https://bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker plugin for OpenStack Heat</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2014-08-30-docker-plugin-for-openstack-he/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2014-08-30-docker-plugin-for-openstack-he/</guid>
      <description>I have been looking at both Docker and OpenStack recently. In my last post I talked a little about the Docker driver for Nova; in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking an in-depth look at the Docker plugin for Heat, which has been available since the Icehouse release but is surprisingly under-documented.
The release announcement on the Docker blog includes an example Heat template, but it is unfortunately grossly inaccurate and has led many people astray.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>