<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gerrit on The Odd Bit</title>
    <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/gerrit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gerrit on The Odd Bit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/gerrit/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sure your Gerrit changes aren&#39;t broken</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2017-01-22-making-sure-your-gerrit-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2017-01-22-making-sure-your-gerrit-change/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an embarrassment when you submit a review to Gerrit only to have it fail CI checks immediately because of something as simple as a syntax error or pep8 failure that you should have caught yourself before submitting&amp;hellip;but you forgot to run your validations before submitting the change.
In many cases you can alleviate this through the use of the git pre-commit hook, which will run every time you commit changes locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gruf gets superpowers</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-19-gruf-gets-superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-19-gruf-gets-superpowers/</guid>
      <description>In my last article article I introduced Gruf, a command line tool for interacting with Gerrit. Since then, Gruf has gained a few important new features.
Caching Gruf will now by default cache results for five minutes. This avoids repeatedly querying the server for the same information when you&amp;rsquo;re just displaying it with different templates (for example, if you run a gruf query open here followed by a gruf -t patches query open here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gruf, a Gerrit command line utility</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-16-gruf-a-gerrit-command-line-uti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-16-gruf-a-gerrit-command-line-uti/</guid>
      <description>(See also the followup to this article.)
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started spending more time interacting with Gerrit, the code review tool used both by OpenStack, at review.openstack.org, and by a variety of other open source projects at GerritForge&amp;rsquo;s GitHub-linked review.gerrithub.io. I went looking for command line tools and was largely disappointed with what I found. Many of the solutions out there assume that you&amp;rsquo;re regularly interacting with a single Gerrit instance, and that&amp;rsquo;s seldom the case: more often, the Gerrit server in use varies from project to project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>