<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on The Odd Bit</title>
    <link>http://blog.oddbit.com/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on The Odd Bit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.oddbit.com/tags/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic maintenance of tag feeds</title>
      <link>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-11-22-automatic-maintenanc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-11-22-automatic-maintenanc/</guid>
      <description>I recently added some scripts to automatically generate tag feeds for my blog when pushing new content. I&amp;rsquo;m using GitHub Pages to publish everything, so it seemed easiest to make tag generation part of a pre-push hook (new in Git 1.8.2). This hook is run automatically as part of the git push operation, so it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect place to insert generated content that must be kept in sync with posts on the blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabled blog comments</title>
      <link>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-11-18-enabled-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-11-18-enabled-comments/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve enabled blog comments using Disqus. This is something of an experiment, since (a) I&amp;rsquo;m not really happy with how Disqus is handling user registration these days and (b) I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I have the time to moderate anything. But we&amp;rsquo;ll see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to GitHub</title>
      <link>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-11-13-moving-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-11-13-moving-to-github/</guid>
      <description>This blog has been hosted on scriptogram for the past year or so. Unfortunately, while I like the publish-via-Dropbox mechanism, there have been enough problems recently that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally switched over to using GitHub Pages for hosting. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about doing this for a while, but the things that finally pushed me to make the change were:
 Sync problems that would prevent new posts from appearing (and that at least once caused posts to disappear).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>