<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardware on The Odd Bit</title>
    <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardware on The Odd Bit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/hardware/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vortex Core Keyboard Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2020-09-26-vortex-core-keyboard-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2020-09-26-vortex-core-keyboard-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on the Vortex Core keyboard for a few months now, and this past week I finally broke down and bought one (with Cherry MX Brown switches). The Vortex Core is a 40% keyboard, which means it consists primarily of letter keys, a few lonely bits of punctuation, and several modifier keys to activate different layers on the keyboard.
 Physical impressions It&amp;rsquo;s a really cute keyboard. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of MX brown switches, and this keyboard is really a joy to type on, at least when you&amp;rsquo;re working primarily with the alpha keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple 1-Wire Buses on the Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2018-03-27-multiple-1-wire-buses-on-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2018-03-27-multiple-1-wire-buses-on-the/</guid>
      <description>The DS18B20 is a popular temperature sensor that uses the 1-Wire protocol for communication. Recent versions of the Linux kernel include a kernel driver for this protocol, making it relatively convenient to connect one or more of these devices to a Raspberry Pi or similar device. 1-Wire devices can be daisy chained, so it is possible to connect several devices to your Pi using only a single GPIO pin, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find many articles out there that describe how to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I2C on the Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-03-12-i2c-on-the-raspberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-03-12-i2c-on-the-raspberry/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my Raspberry Pi to communicate with my Arduino via I2C. The Raspberry Pi is a 3.3v device and the Arduino is a 5v device. While in general this means that you need to use a level converter when connecting the two devices, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to use a level converter when connecting the Arduino to the Raspberry Pi via I2C.
The design of the I2C bus is such that the only device driving a voltage on the bus is the master (in this case, the Raspberry Pi), via pull-up resistors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interrupt driven GPIO with Python</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-03-08-interrupt-driven-gpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-03-08-interrupt-driven-gpi/</guid>
      <description>There are several Python libraries out there for interacting with the GPIO pins on a Raspberry Pi:
 RPi.GPIO The WiringPi bindings for Python, and The Quick2Wire Python API (which depends on Python 3)  All of them are reasonably easy to use, but the Quick2Wire API provides a uniquely useful feature: epoll-enabled GPIO interrupts. This makes it trivial to write code that efficiently waits for and responds to things like button presses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling a servo with your Arduino</title>
      <link>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-03-07-controlling-a-servo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2013-03-07-controlling-a-servo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started playing with an Arduino kit I purchased a year ago (and only just now got around to unboxing). I purchased the kit from SparkFun, and it includes a motley collection of resistors, LEDs, a motor, a servo, and more.
I was fiddling around with this exercise, which uses the SoftwareServo library to control a servo. Using this library, you just pass it an angle and the library takes care of everything else, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
