<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>The Odd Bit</title>

  
  <link rel="self" href="https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/tripleo/atom.xml"/>
  
  <link href="https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/tripleo/" rel="alternate"></link>

  <updated>2019-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.oddbit.com/tag/tripleo/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Running Keystone with Docker Compose</title>
    <author>
      <name>Lars Kellogg-Stedman</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2019-06-07-running-keystone-with-docker-c/"/>
    <id>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2019-06-07-running-keystone-with-docker-c/</id>
    <published>2019-06-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">In this article, we will look at what is necessary to run OpenStack&amp;rsquo;s Keystone service (and the requisite database server) in containers using Docker Compose.
Running MariaDB The standard mariadb docker image can be configured via a number of environment variables. It also benefits from persistent volume storage, since in most situations you don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose your data when you remove a container. A simple docker command line for starting MariaDB might look something like:</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Connecting another vm to your tripleo-quickstart deployment</title>
    <author>
      <name>Lars Kellogg-Stedman</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-05-19-connecting-another-vm-to-your-tripleo-qu/"/>
    <id>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-05-19-connecting-another-vm-to-your-tripleo-qu/</id>
    <published>2016-05-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you have set up an environment using tripleo-quickstart and you would like to add another virtual machine to the mix that has both &amp;ldquo;external&amp;rdquo; connectivity (&amp;ldquo;external&amp;rdquo; in quotes because I am using it in the same way as the quickstart does w/r/t the undercloud) and connectivity to the overcloud nodes. How would you go about setting that up?
For a concrete example, let&amp;rsquo;s presume you have deployed an environment using the default tripleo-quickstart configuration, which looks like this:</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Deploying an HA OpenStack development environment with tripleo-quickstart
</title>
    <author>
      <name>Lars Kellogg-Stedman</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-19-deploy-an-ha-openstack-development-envir/"/>
    <id>https://blog.oddbit.com/post/2016-02-19-deploy-an-ha-openstack-development-envir/</id>
    <published>2016-02-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html">In this article I would like to introduce tripleo-quickstart, a tool that will automatically provision a virtual environment and then use TripleO to deploy an HA OpenStack on top of it.
Introducing Tripleo-Quickstart The goal of the Tripleo-Quickstart project is to replace the instack-virt-setup tool for quickly setting up virtual TripleO environments, and to ultimately become the tool used by both developers and upstream CI for this purpose. The project is a set of Ansible playbooks that will take care of:</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
